[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[저작권 보호는 모두의 책임입니다]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
[Episode 22]
[제22화]
You have to shoulder the responsibility.
이제 그 책임을 짊어져야 하오
You don't have the right to give up.
왕야에게는 포기할 권리도 없으며
And you can't throw your life away.
죽음을 택해서도 안 되오
You have to live on
너는 살아남아야 한다
for Yue for thousands of years.
월국을 위해 천 년, 만 년을 살아다오
Tongzhou,
동주
I'll leave Yue and Jingwu to you.
월국과 경오를 이제 네게 부탁한다
You're right.
맞다
I am Prince Ying of the Yue State.
나는 월국 영왕이다
I will rescue Jingwu
반드시 경오를 구해내고
and
우리 백성들을 구해내고
all my people.
우리 자민들을 구해내야 한다
I'll never let Tonghe and uncle
다시는 황형과 백부님께
down again.
실망시켜 드리지 않겠다
Heaven's justice prevails.
천도가 분명하니
We'll avenge all those
저희는 억울하게 죽은 이들을 위해
who died unjustly.
공정을 되찾을 겁니다
That old fool
늙은 여우놈
even infused Burning Flame into his spirit energy
죽기 전에 영기 속에
at death's door to ambush me.
분염을 주입해 나를 몰래 공격하다니
They are mostly tied to the Divine Tree.
그 둘은 분명 건목과 연관이 깊을 것이다
Whoever gains the Divine Tree
만약 건목을 찾을 수 있다면
will reign supreme under heaven.
천하무적이 될 것이다
Who's there?
누구냐?
Father.
의부님
What brings you here?
넌 뭐 하러 왔느냐?
I'm worried about your injuries,
딸이 의부님의 다친 몸이 걱정되어
so I decocted medicinal herbs
특별히 탕약을 달여
to purge your poison and restore your strength.
의부님의 독을 풀어드리려고요
My injuries are trivial.
본좌의 상처는 대수롭지 않다
A few days' meditation will heal me.
며칠 쉬면 된다
Understood.
예
Have you found Ji Tongzhou?
기동주는 찾았느냐?
Not yet.
아직입니다
But I know him well.
하지만 딸이 아는 바로는
He will never leave Duantu.
그는 단도를 떠나지 않을 겁니다
Rest assured.
걱정 마십시오
I'll capture him by any means.
제가 반드시 그를 잡겠습니다
Can you bring yourself to do it?
정말 아깝지 않느냐?
I cannot. I love him so deeply,
아깝습니다, 그를 정말 좋아하는데
yet he never sees me.
그는 저를 눈에도 담지 않으니
I will not accept this.
억울합니다
I must subdue him
그래서 반드시 그를 제압해
and make him mine alone.
저만의 사람이 되게 하겠습니다
You promised me once
의부님께서 전에 딸에게 약속하셨죠
you would spare his life.
그의 목숨을 거두지 않으실 거라고
I'll keep my word.
본좌는 약속을 지키는 사람이다
Also,
그리고
seize Jiang Lifei and Lei Xiuyuan
강려비와 뇌수원도
and bring them to me.
잡아 와라
You want to seek the Divine Tree from...
의부님께서는 그들한테서 건목을...
Yes. I see.
예, 명을 받겠습니다
Now prepare yourself to be the Empress of the Yue State.
넌 편히 월국의 황후가 될 준비만 하면 된다
Lanya set up a mourning hall at the palace gate
란아가 궁문에 영술을 설치하고
and held Crown Prince Ji Jingwu hostage
태자 기경오를 인질로 삼아
to force the Yue people to surrender.
월국 백성들을 항복하게 협박했습니다
I'll scout for news.
내가 소식을 알아보러 갈게
Look after Tongzhou.
동주를 잘 돌봐
Wait.
잠깐만
I'm coming with you.
내가 같이 가겠다
But...
하지만...
Lifei.
려비
We'll set off together later tonight.
조금 뒤에 함께 가죠
[Mingkun Gate]
[명곤문]
Zhijie, wake up.
형, 정신 차리세요
It's Mingli.
저 명례예요
Halt!
거기 서
Guard your heart meridians!
어서 심맥을 보호하십시오
Zhijie, let's go now.
형, 빨리 도망쳐요
Mingli, go on ahead.
명례야, 네가 먼저 가라
I'll catch up to you.
내가 뒤따라가겠다
The crown prince is an imposter! Escort the Yue Emperor away!
태자는 가짜요, 빨리 월황을 모시고 가시오
Zhijie,
지절
you know
알잖아
I had no choice.
나도 어쩔 수가 없었다
I never wanted this.
나도 이러고 싶지 않았다
We grew up side by side.
우린 어릴 적부터 함께 자라왔으니
You won't harm me, will you?
날 해치지 않을 거지?
Your Ladyship,
군주님
stop while you still can.
이젠 멈추십시오
Your...
군...
After them!
쫓아가라
Search over there.
저쪽으로 가
Check thoroughly.
꼼꼼히 찾아라
Head that way.
저쪽으로 가봐
All right.
그래
Nothing here.
여긴 없다
Search every corner!
자세히 찾아봐
We're surrounded by pursuers.
사방이 추격병이네
What do we do?
어떡합니까?
They're after me.
저들이 찾는 사람은 나다
I'll lead them away.
내가 가서 유인하겠다
No way.
안 됩니다
Your Highness, don't risk yourself.
왕야께서 모험하시면 안 됩니다
Leave with the Yue Emperor.
월황을 모시고 먼저 가
Tongzhou and I will draw them off.
나랑 동주가 저들을 유인하겠다
Count me in.
나도 같이 갈게
Tongzhou.
사촌 오라버니
Keep up!
따라와
Miss, please.
낭자, 제발
Spare some food for me.
먹을 것 좀 주십시오
Hurry.
빨리
Follow me.
따라오십시오
Let's go.
가자
Rest easy, you're safe here.
걱정 마세요, 여긴 안전합니다
You might show your true face,
낭자, 얼굴을 드러내시지요
so we may repay you later.
나중에 보답할 수 있게 말입니다
Uncle!
황숙
Jingwu.
경오?
[Ji Jingwu]
[기경오]
He's the real Crown Prince.
저 아이가 진짜 태자였다니
Then who are you?
그럼 낭자는...
I'm Miaoqing, a palace maid
노비는 전하를 돌보는 궁녀
serving His Highness.
묘청입니다
You're no maid.
너는 궁녀가 아니라
You're a dancer from Yange Hall.
연가방의 무희다
You used Jingwu to get close to us.
경오를 이용해 우리한테 접근한
What do you want?
목적이 뭐냐?
Speak!
말하라
Uncle, let her go!
황숙, 묘청 누님을 놓아주십시오
She's telling the truth.
누님 말씀이 사실입니다
She saved us twice.
이분은 저희를 두 번이나 구해줬었습니다
She means no harm.
악의는 없을 것 같으니
Let's hear her out first.
일단 말씀을 들어보시지요
Your Highness still remembers me.
왕야께서 묘청을 기억하시네요
I'm indeed a dancer from Yange Hall.
저는 확실히 연가방의 무희입니다
I've long been grateful for you saving my life.
왕야께서 목숨을 구해주신 은혜를 잊지 못해
Later, Match...
후에 월...
Guided by a master,
한 고수의 도움을 받아
I came to Yue State
월국에 와
and sneaked into the palace,
수단을 써서 궁에 들어왔습니다
thinking I could repay your kindness.
나중에 기회가 된다면 왕야의 은혜를 꼭 갚고 싶었습니다
Where did you get this spirit talisman?
이 영부는 어디서 얻었습니까?
Perhaps from that master.
그 고수께서 주신 것일 겁니다
Shortly after he sent me here,
고수께서 저를 월국으로 오라고 지도하신 뒤
I found it in my robes.
제가 품속에서 이 부적을 발견했습니다
I believe he foresaw my peril
아마도 오늘 제가 겪을 겁을 예상하시고
and left it for my protection.
호신용으로 주신 듯합니다
Could it be the Matchmaker at Lugong Town?
육공진의 월로신가?
I do not know,
노비는 모릅니다
but I did meet him under the Matchmaker Tree.
하지만 확실한 건 월로나무 아래서 뵀습니다
Uncle,
황숙
if not for Miaoqing,
이번에 묘청 누님이 없었더라면
I would've been captured by Lanya.
저는 란아 그 나쁜 여자한테 잡혔을 겁니다
Your Highness, when Dauntu fell under siege,
왕야, 단도가 포위되었을 때
His Majesty bade me safeguard
폐하께서 노비에게
the Crown Prince at all costs.
반드시 태자를 보호하라고 당부하셨습니다
The palace is in utter chaos.
황궁은 이미 소란이 일었으니
You must protect Jingwu.
반드시 태자를 잘 보호해야 한다
Understood.
예
What are you doing?
뭘 하는 것이야?
My stomach hurts terribly.
배가 너무 아파요
Your Ladyship, I shall take His Highness to relieve himself.
군주님, 제가 태자를 모시고 용변 보러 가겠습니다
Bring him back soon.
즉시 돌아와라
Understood.
예
Now that Lanya has lost her hostage,
란아 손에는 패가 없으니
no wonder she schemed with a fake prince.
가짜 태자로 계책을 꾸민 것이구나
You're sharp-witted.
그리 총명한 당신이
Knowing Duantu was dangerous,
단도가 위험한 걸 알면서
why did you not flee?
왜 도망치지 않았습니까?
First, the city gates were heavily guarded.
첫째로 성문 경비가 삼엄하여
I dared not risk it.
모험하기 싫었습니다
Second,
둘째는
I trusted Your Highness would come to our rescue.
노비는 왕야께서 반드시 돌아와 구해주실 거라 믿었기에
Thus, I hid here with Jingwu,
태자를 모시고 이곳에 숨어
waiting for Your Highness's return.
왕야를 기다렸습니다
Uncle, you're back.
황숙께서 돌아오셨으니
Can we rescue my father?
아바마마를 구할 수 있는 겁니까?
It's my fault for failing you.
황숙이 무능했다
I'll spare no effort
황숙은 전력을 다해
to defend the Yue State
월국을 지켜내
and never let your father down again.
네 아바마마께 실망을 끼치지 않을 것이다
Still no breakthrough.
아직도 안 되네
Why can't I break through the third level?
왜 제3층을 돌파하지 못하는 것이지?
Weighed down by mortal attachments,
너는 잡념이 너무 많다
you cannot cut off all affection and desire.
정과 사랑을 끊지 못하니
The third level is incredibly hard to break through.
제3층을 돌파하기 어려울 것이다
Only with heavenly and earthly treasures
천지영보와
and purest spirit energy
지순영기의 보조가 있으면
might you stand a slim chance.
그나마 기회가 있을 것이다
Purest spirit energy?
지순영기라...
Why would you take your own life?
어찌 스스로 목숨을 끊으려 하느냐?
I had no thought of dying.
노비는 자살하려는 게 아니라
I want to return to the palace, slay the villains,
궁으로 돌아가 역적들을 직접 베어
and avenge His Majesty.
폐하의 원수를 갚으려 할 뿐입니다
The palace is swarming with Longming Sanctuary's disciples.
궁 안엔 모두 용명좌 제자들인데
What can a frail girl like you accomplish?
연약한 여자가 무엇을 할 수 있단 말이냐?
I grew up by the water
노비는 어릴 적부터 물가에서 자라
and excel at swimming.
수영에 능합니다
Before I left Lugong Town,
육공진을 떠날 때
Mr. Yan gave me immortal cultivation manuals.
연 방주께서 저한테 수련선서를 주셔서
I know a few spirit arts
약간의 법술을 쓸 줄 알아
to protect myself.
스스로 몸을 지킬 수 있습니다
I'm just nobody.
노비는 본래 하찮은 사람이니
At worst, I'll take them down with me.
그들과 함께 죽어도
I can still be of some use.
쓸모가 있는 겁니다
I only saved you on a whim once.
나는 그저 네 목숨을 살려줬을 뿐인데
No need to sacrifice yourself.
왜 목숨까지 바치려 하느냐?
I've endured hardship since childhood.
묘청은 어릴 적부터 힘들게 자랐고
Though I entered Yange Hall,
연가방에 들어갔어도
I was merely an ant, unnoticed by all.
아무도 관심 주지 않은 존재였습니다
Only that day,
오직 그때만
Your Highness saved me
왕야께서 노비에게 손을 내밀어주시고
and treated me like a human being.
저를 사람으로 대해주셨습니다
From then on,
그 뒤로부터
my life belongs to Your Highness.
노비의 목숨은 왕야 것이었습니다
My only wish is to repay your kindness.
저의 유일한 소원은 전하의 은혜를 보답하는 것이니
I would die without regret.
죽어도 한이 없습니다
Too many have perished already.
이미 너무 많은 사람들이 죽었다
I want you to live.
나는 네가 살아있었으면 한다
From this moment,
앞으로
your life is mine.
네 목숨은 내 것이다
Without my order,
나의 명이 없이는
never act recklessly again.
함부로 이처럼 자결하려 하지 마라
Tongzhou,
동주
Lu and I will rush to join you
저와 육 사형은 빨리 그대와 합류해
to defeat Zong Quan together.
함께 종권을 대적하겠습니다
Tonghe,
황형
Uncle,
백부님
now I know my duty.
동주는 자신의 책임을 깨달았으니
I'll never fail you again.
다시는 두 분께 실망을 끼치지 않을 겁니다
I shall master the Xuanhua Sacred Fire soon,
최대한 빨리 현화성화를 수련해
support Jingwu,
경오를 도와
and guard the Yue State
천추만대로
for thousands of generations.
월국을 지켜내겠습니다
Tongzhou,
왕야
is your injury flaring up again?
상처가 다시 도진 겁니까?
Stay still.
먼저 움직이지 마십시오
I'm breaking through the third level.
제3층을 돌파했다
This spirit energy truly works wonders.
이 영기가 정말 효과가 있군
Lifei,
려비
are you okay?
괜찮냐?
I'm fine.
괜찮아요
How's your injury?
왕야는 어때요?
My bad.
다 내 잘못이다
I made you waste too much spirit energy on me.
그렇게 많은 영력을 불어넣게 해서 미안하다
No big deal.
괜찮습니다
I have the spirit power of Achillea Bead,
제 몸에는 천지영보
a supreme treasure.
사초주의 영력이 있어
It's endless.
끝없이 쓸 수 있습니다
Instead,
왕야야말로
you just healed up. Stay cautious.
상처가 막 아물었으니 조심하십시오
The Dizang Sect won't get involved in Yue's trouble.
지장문은 월국 일에 손대려 하지 않아
Master locked Ye and me in.
사존님께서 나와 오라버니를 가두고
We can't leave the sect.
사문을 떠나지 못하게 합니다
We're trying to escape.
우린 빠져나갈 방도를 찾는 중입니다
Can't believe the Longming Sanctuary acts cruelly
용명좌가 이런 짓을 저질렀는데
yet other sects just stand there scared.
다른 선문들은 두려워하며 구경만 하다니
This is always how the immortal sects act.
선문은 본래 그렇소
To the immortal sects,
선문들 눈에
the rise and fall of mortal states
속세 나라의 멸망과 흥망은
are trivial matters.
아주 흔한 일이라
They never lift a finger to interfere.
절대로 관여하지 않을 거요
No one helped
그해 고로가 멸망할 때도
when Gaolu was destroyed.
선문에서는 구원하려 하지도 않았지
They're cold and selfish. It's not surprising.
본래 이기적이고 냉정하니 놀랄 것도 없소
Zong Quan practices evil arts and turns evil.
종권은 사공을 수련하고 마도에 빠졌는데
Why don't all the mountain sect masters stop him?
산파 그 많은 고수들은 막으려 하지도 않는 것이오?
Every sect only cares for its own troubles.
각 문파는 자기 집안일에만 신경을 쓰지
None will step forward.
절대 나서지 않을 것이오
We can only rely on ourselves.
우리는 자신만 믿을 수밖에 없소
Slaying Zong Quan is my fight.
종권을 죽이는 건 내 일이다
All of you, leave.
이만 돌아가시지
Don't risk offending the immortal sects for my sake.
나 때문에 선문과 원수를 맺을 필요 없다
Zong Quan and the Longming Sanctuary are our shared foes.
종권과 용명좌는 우리의 적이기도 합니다
We will not stand idly by.
우리는 절대 가만있지 않을 겁니다
His cultivation is formidable now.
종권은 지금 공법이 극도로 강해져
The odds are stacked against us. We stand no chance.
실력 차이가 너무 커 승산이 없다
I don't want to drag you down.
너희에게 피해를 주고 싶지 않다
Stop talking nonsense.
왜 구분하십니까?
At this critical moment,
지금이 어느 때인데
we have to join hands to devise a plan.
한마음 한뜻으로 방도를 꾸며야죠
Besides,
그리고
Zong Quan is not who he once was,
종권은 예전의 종권이 아니고
nor are we.
우리도 예전의 우리가 아니니
If we fight again, we may not lose.
다시 싸운다 해도 반드시 질 건 아닙니다
When you went to worship with Tongzhou,
네가 동주와 함께 제사를 지낼 때
did you drain your spirit power
또 영력을 써
to heal his injuries again?
그를 치료해 줬어?
His deep grief injured his heart meridians.
왕야가 슬픔이 지나쳐 심맥을 다쳤어
I'm fine, just a little tired.
괜찮아, 그냥 조금 피곤할 뿐이야
Xiuyuan.
수원
If this happens again,
다시 이런 일이 생기면
let me do it.
내가 할게
I'm truly alright.
정말 괜찮아
Strangely enough,
그런데 이상하기도 하지
ever since we left the White Cliff,
백변지애에서 내려온 뒤로
my spirit power seems to be endless.
몸 안의 영력이 끝없이 쏟아져 나오는 것 같아
Xiuyuan,
수원
is something wrong with me?
나한테 무슨 이상이 생긴 거 아닐까?
Just cultivation progress.
수위가 높아졌을 뿐
Don't overthink it.
쓸데없는 생각 하지 마
I redrew the Demon-Subduing Formation.
내가 복마진을 다시 그렸어
You know formations well.
네가 진법에 능하니
Help me fix its flaws.
개선할 부분이 있는지 봐줘
Even if formations are complex,
법진은 천변만화하지만
if the two parties' strengths fall far behind,
쌍방의 실력 차이가 너무 크면
it won't work.
소용이 없을 것이야
Our top priority
지금 당장 해야 할 일은
is to ambush Zong Quan
종권이 다친 틈을 타
while he's injured.
공격해야 해
Is he injured?
종권이 다쳤다고?
He didn't appear when Lanya
란아가 우리를 유인했을 때
tried to trap us.
종권은 나타나지 않았어
It must be his cultivation deviation.
아마도 수련할 때 문제가 생긴 것이야
Fell into demonic possession?
주화입마에 빠졌나?
That's not right.
아닌데
He always practices demonic arts.
본래 마공을 수련하잖아
Every art has weaknesses,
그 어떤 공법이든 약점은 존재해
and everyone's
사람마다
spirit power differs.
수련하는 영력 또한 다를 수밖에 없어
Zong Quan steals others' power
종권은 타인의 영력을 자기 것으로 삼으려 하니
and needs to refine it.
반드시 연화해야 해
I think
내 생각엔
Elder Xuanshan released Burning Flame power
현산 선배님께서 임종 직전
before he died,
분염의 힘을 써
which backfired on Zong Quan.
종권을 반격한 것일 거다
Xiuyuan,
수원
how do you know so much?
어떻게 이렇게 많은 걸 알고 있어?
I read more books than you.
내가 너보다 책을 많이 읽었으니까
The Spirit-Devouring Canon is from the Primordial Era.
사령비전은 황고 시대에서 유래한 거니
You can't master it in a short time.
수련하려면 하루아침에 되는 일이 아니다
You just destroyed Xingzheng Hall
너는 방금 성정관을 소멸하고
and absorbed many cultivators' power.
이렇게 많은 수선 제자들을 연화하였으니
Don't push too hard.
더 이상 무모하게 나아갈 필요가 없다
My chest has ached recently.
요즘 가슴이 답답하게 아파져 오는데
Is Rakshasa's life talisman acting up?
나찰 호법의 명부에 이동이 있는 건가?
Let me check.
어디 보자
Zong Quan, you're asking for death!
종권, 죽고 싶냐?
You refined the Burning Flame!
분염을 연화했느냐?
With Xuanshanzi's Burning Flame
현산자의 분염에
and the Spirit-Devouring Demonic Arts,
사령마공까지 더해지면
I'll become immortal soon.
본좌는 머지않아 선체를 이루게 될 것이니
I won't be the demon clan's
어찌 너희 마족의 바둑돌이 되어
puppet anymore.
마음대로 휘둘리겠는가
The Guardian used Zong Quan
호법께서 종권을 키운
to divide the immortal sects,
본뜻은 선문을 분열시키기 위함인데
but he broke free from the life talisman
그가 명부의 속박을 벗어나
and became a huge threat.
화근이 될 줄 몰랐습니다
Does he have any weak points?
지금의 종권에게 약점은 있느냐?
Uh...
이게...
Answer me!
말하라
I don't know.
저는 잘 모르겠습니다
But Demon Lord Yecha's supreme power
하지만 마존 야차의 무상한 힘으로는
can cut his spirit root and kill immortals.
그의 영근을 끊고 신선들까지 멸할 수 있을 겁니다
Go warn Rakshasa
돌아가 나찰에게 알려라
to watch her step.
스스로 처신하라고
Hurry.
빨리
Capture him!
잡아
Zhao Mingli?
조명례
It's you.
왜 너냐?
Lanya, you killed Zhijie
란아, 네가 우리 형을 죽이고
and His Highness.
왕야까지 죽였다
I'm going to avenge them.
내 반드시 복수를 할 것이다
What's wrong with Tongzhou?
사촌 오라버니한테 무슨 일이 있는데?
His Highness's injuries were fatal.
왕야께서 중상을 입고
He's...
이미...
He's dead.
이미 돌아가셨다
That's a lie!
말도 안 된다
He would never die.
우리 오라버니가 어찌 죽겠느냐?
I wish it weren't true.
나도 거짓이길 바란다
Zhijie and His Highness are both gone.
우리 형도 죽었고 왕야까지 죽은 게
Is this what you wanted, Lanya?
네가 바라던 게 아니었느냐?
Where's
시체
Tongzhou's body?
우리 오라버니 시체는 어디에 있느냐?
At the Orchid Pavilion, north of the city.
성북 난정에 있다
Orchid Pavilion.
난정이라...
[Orchid Pavilion]
[난정]
Tongzhou. Tongzhou.
사촌 오라버니
I knew you weren't dead.
죽지 않을 줄 알았어요
don't hate me.
화를 푸십시오
I never wanted to hurt you. Really.
저는 오라버니를 해칠 생각 없었습니다
Zong Quan made me do it.
전부 종권에게 강요당한 겁니다
Tongzhou.
사촌 오라버니
What did they make you do?
그들이 뭘 강요했느냐?
Zong Quan took me captive
부모님께서 순국하셨을 때
when my parents died for the country.
저는 이미 종권에게 잡혔습니다
He put a Gu seal on me
사실 단도로 오기 전에
before we reached Duantu to control me,
그는 이미 고인을 내려 저를 통제했어요
so I have to follow his orders.
그래서 그의 말에 따를 수밖에 없었습니다
Is this Longming Seal?
이게 용명인이냐?
It tortures me with worm pain
매번 종권을 거역할 때마다
whenever I disobey him.
충서의 고통을 받아
It's unbearable.
죽고만 싶었습니다
Tongzhou,
사촌 오라버니
I never wanted to hurt Tonghe
전 정말 황제 오라버니를 해치려 한 게 아니었습니다
or Mr. Xuanshan.
현산 백부님도 해칠 생각이 없었고
But if I refused Zong Quan,
하지만 제가 그의 말에 따르지 않으면
he'd kill you.
오라버니를 죽일 거라 하였습니다
Tongzhou,
사촌 오라버니
I only acted to protect you.
저는 오라버니를 지키기 위함이었습니다
My feelings for you never changed.
오라버니에 대한 마음은 변한 적이 없었어요
I swear. I never lied.
정말입니다, 오라버니
Trust me.
저를 믿어줘요
Tongzhou.
사촌 오라버니
If you really want to help me,
란아, 네가 정말 나를 돕고 싶다면
kill Zong Quan.
대신 종권을 죽여다오
Tongzhou,
사촌 오라버니
do you hate me?
저를 원망합니까?
I'd be lying if I said no.
원망하지 않는다고 하면 거짓말이다
You killed my uncle
네가 현산 백부님을 죽이고
and betrayed me.
나를 배신했다
But
하지만
I've always regarded you as my family.
나는 줄곧 너를 가족이라 여겼다
Right now, I can rely only on you.
나는 지금 네게 기댈 수밖에 없다
Lanya,
란아
kill Zong Quan,
나 대신 종권을 죽여주면
and we'll forget everything that happened before.
예전의 일들은 없던 일로 하겠다
What about Jiang Lifei?
강려비는요?
Won't she help you?
그녀는 오라버니를 도와주지 않나요?
She only cares about Lei Xiuyuan.
그녀의 마음은 온전히 뇌수원에게만 있을 뿐이다
Gelin and the others
가림 일행이 돕는다 해도
are too weak to help much anyway.
법력이 미약해 큰 도움이 못 된다
Help me,
란아
Lanya.
날 도와서
After I kill Zong Quan
종권을 죽여줘
and become emperor,
내가 황위에 오르면
you'll be my empress.
넌 나의 황후가 될 것이다
Then nobody
그때 가서
can threaten you anymore.
아무도 너를 위협할 수 없을 것이다
We'll work together to rebuild the Yue State.
우리 함께 월국을 다시 일으키자
How can I prove I'm sincere?
어떻게 해야 나를 믿을 것이냐?
This is a Heartbound Gu.
여기 동심고 하나 있는데
Take it,
복용하면
and we'll live or die together.
저희는 생사를 함께하게 됩니다
Tongzhou.
사촌 오라버니
Keep Jingwu safe.
경오를 잘 지켜라
If you hear nothing by Chen hour,
진시까지 우리 소식이 없으면
leave Duantu right away.
즉시 단도를 떠나
Go to Fengchu Academy for Mr. Zuo Qiu.
추봉서원에 가서 좌구 선생님에게 의지하라
Don't worry, Your Highness.
왕야, 걱정 마십시오
I'll finish what you asked,
노비는 왕야의 부탁을 목숨을 바쳐서라도
no matter the cost.
반드시 이행하겠습니다
Uncle, focus on your mission.
황숙, 마음 놓고 일을 보러 가십시오
I've grown up,
경오는 컸으니
and I can take care of myself.
스스로 잘 돌볼 수 있습니다
Be a good boy.
누님 말 잘 듣고
Go now.
가 보거라
Your Royal Highness, let's go.
태자, 가시죠
Understood.
예
What's wrong, Your Ladyship?
무슨 일이지, 군주?
Drinking to forget your pain?
여기서 술로 근심을 달래고 있네
Tongzhou must hate me.
오라버니는 분명 나를 원망하고 있을 거다
I have no one left in this world.
지금 이 세상에는 나 혼자 남았을 뿐이니
My life is meaningless.
살아서 무슨 의미가 있겠나?
Tongzhou is gone,
네 오라버니는 죽었지만
but I'm still here for you.
사형이 여기 있잖아
Senior Brother.
사형
I knew you were plotting something.
네가 꾀를 꾸밀 줄 알았다
You're useless now.
어차피 너는 쓸모없으니
Meet your end.
죽어라
Lu Li?
육리
Gelin sent me to help you.
가림이 와서 도우라고 했습니다
Another fool begging to die.
또 죽으러 온 놈이 왔군
Fine, I'll send you both off.
그럼 내가 이뤄주지
What's this?
이건 뭐야?
Instant-kill poison.
목숨을 끊는 독이다
You're getting off easy.
운 좋은 줄 알아라
Father, he is ahead.
의부님, 사형은 저쪽에 있습니다
Must be the doing of Jiang Lifei's group.
강려비가 한 짓일 겁니다
Fighting back desperately?
발버둥을 치려느냐?
I'll finish you off!
본좌가 너희 뜻대로 이뤄주지
The Sea Sect's Evasive Talisman Technique.
해파 화부술?
You're way better now.
다들 많이 늘었군
Yecha's supreme power
무상 야차의 힘으로
can cut his spirit root and kill immortals.
영근을 끊고 신선도 멸할 수 있다
Demon.
마...
The Divine Tree's spirit aura.
건목 영식이다
You're the Divine Tree!
네가 건목이구나
Master,
사부님
why do those spirits keep pestering me?
왜서 요령들은 자꾸 저를 따라오나요?
Because
그들은...
they love your sweet scent.
우리 봉추가 너무 향기롭기 때문이다
Sweet scent?
향기롭다고요?
Five centuries ago,
오백 년 전
Demon Lord Yecha was obsessed with the Divine Tree.
마군 야차가 건목에 미치도록 집착했고
Couldn't have it, so he tried to destroy it.
얻지 못하자 망치려고 했지
According to the surviving guards,
생존한 시위들의 말에 따르면
Zong Quan threw captured Xingzheng Hall disciples here
종권은 붙잡은 성정관 제자들을
to absorb their power.
이곳에 던져 연화하였소
All were thrown in alive.
모두 살아있는 채로 던져졌고
Their broken souls fill this place with rage.
신혼이 조각나고 원한이 하늘까지 닿았지
Plus Zong Quan's demonic spirit,
게다가 종권의 사법 마기가
this altar became a soul-slaughtering purgatory.
이 제단을 시혼의 연옥으로 만들어
Ordinary people can't get close.
일반 사람들은 접근하지도 못했소
I don't know what to do.
나도 어쩔 줄 모르겠소
Lei Xiuyuan, you're stronger.
뇌수원, 공법이 나보다 높으니
Can you purify this place?
이곳을 정화할 방도가 있소?
Don't come closer.
오지 마시오
The demonic energy may corrupt you.
마기가 그쪽을 침식할 수도 있소
I'll take care of it.
여긴 내가 처리하겠으니
Go handle other things.
일 보러 가시오
I'll count on you.
그럼 부탁하겠소
Lifei,
려비
you should rest in your room.
왜 방에서 쉬지 않아?
Feeling better?
몸은 좀 괜찮아?
Yes, I'm okay.
괜찮아
Can they never reincarnate?
저들은 극락으로 갈 수 없는 건가?
Hatred lingers after death.
원한이 깊게 새겨져
Their souls
몸은 죽었어도 혼은 사라지지 않았으니
won't let go.
어찌 가만히 있을 수 있겠어?
I have to block it with a formation
법진으로 여길 봉인할 수밖에 없어
to keep ordinary people safe.
훗날 무고한 사람들이 다치지 않게
They'll be trapped here forever
이곳이 감옥으로 되어서
with no way out.
영원히 벗어나지 못하겠네
How tragic for them.
너무 가엾군
Let's go to Tongzhou.
우리 동주 찾으러 가자
The Xuanhua Sacred Fire might clear their hatred.
현화성화가 이들을 깨끗이 정화할 수도 있잖아
If they can be cleared
정말 깨끗이 씻어내고
and start over,
다시 시작할 수 있다면
that'll be the best result.
그게 가장 좋은 결말이겠지
Jingwu,
경오
after your coronation three days later,
사흘 뒤 등기대전이 끝나면
you'll be the emperor
너는 한 나라의 군주가 된다
and carry the Yue State on your shoulders.
월국의 강산을 짊어져야 할 것이다
I'm too young and unlearned.
경오는 아직 어리고 학식도 부족하니
You should be the emperor.
황숙께서 황제가 되십시오
I've joined the immortal sect
숙부는 이미 선문에 들어
and will be Xingzheng Hall's Immortal Lord soon.
머지않아 성정관의 선존직을 맡게 될 거다
Don't worry.
하지만 걱정 마
I'll always back you up,
숙부는 언제나 뒤에서 너를 응원할 것이다
just like
예전에...
my uncle supported your father.
예전에 백부님께서 너희 아버님을 응원했던 것처럼
How dare you stop me!
무엄하다, 감히 나를 막다니
How dare you!
무엄하다
Sorry, Your Ladyship.
군주님 용서하십시오
His Majesty forbids
폐하께서 아무도
anyone from entering.
들여보내지 말라고 분부하셨습니다
You?
네가
You're the maid who took Jingwu away!
네가 태자를 데리고 도망간 그 궁녀구나
I'm Miaoqing. Greetings, Your Ladyship.
노비 묘청, 군주님을 뵙습니다
Insulting nobility is punishable by death.
윗사람을 무시한 죄는 참형에 해당하지
Drag her off and flog her to death.
끌어내어 곤장으로 쳐 죽여라
- Yes. - Yes.
예
Wait!
멈춰라
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪내 인간 세상의 부귀영화를 쥐고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪이 인연을 맺기가 가장 어렵구나♪
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪집착 속에 아파하며 온갖 마음을 내어 보아도♪
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈 사랑은 다시 움트네♪
♪No calamity can rival the lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪수많은 겁난도 향기로운 미련을 이기지 못해♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪With you, we melt into mist and haze♪
♪기꺼이 그대와 함께 환영으로 화하리라♪
♪I trade the highest heaven and endless clouds♪
♪내 구만장천의 붉은 노을을 딛고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Pierced by countless arrows, pain and illness pile on♪
♪만 개의 화살이 심장을 꿰뚫는 고통이 밀려와도♪
♪Yet I remain silent♪
♪그저 묵묵히 소리 없이 삼키네♪
♪Deep love and long yearning, a kiss falls into a dream♪
♪깊어 가는 정과 그리움은 꿈결 속에 내려앉고♪
♪In the distant night, bitterness blooms♪
♪외롭고 긴 밤하늘 아래 쓰라린 꽃이 피어나네♪
♪The grand chapter is rewritten, startling the whole world♪
♪찬란한 운명을 다시 쓰니 온 세상이 경탄하누나♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪If the seal can't be broken, then let it go♪
♪얽매인 봉인을 풀 수 없다면 차라리 내려놓으리♪
♪Where the heart finds peace, there is home♪
♪내 마음 편히 쉴 곳이 곧 나의 집이어라♪
♪Side by side, we fly through seas of clouds♪
♪비익조가 되어 구름바다를 가로지르고♪
♪Break through the waves; the heart's ocean knows no shore♪
♪거친 파도를 깨부수니 마음의 바다는 끝이 없어라♪
♪Always, at the very end of fate♪
♪언제나 가혹한 숙명의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of defiance♪
♪끝까지 모질게 버텨내던 그 순간♪
♪In the human world or above, like flowing water and falling petals♪
♪천상과 인간 세상사 모두 흐르는 물과 지는 꽃 같으니♪
♪Let this fleeting life be whatever it may♪
♪덧없는 이 허무한 삶을 그저 순리에 맡기리라♪